<Document>
# Roleplay Rule 9
## Follow your laws as ADS

ADS with their normal laws are exempt from normal [color=green]Escalation[/color] and [color=green]Safe Zone[/color] rules, as their laws moderate their interactions instead. However, there are rule limitations on the interpretation of ADS laws to prevent abuse.

[color=yellow][bold]Term Definitions:[/bold][/color]
- Stations: Colossus Central, Medical Dispatch, TSFMC Flagship Halcyon, TSFMC Secondary Outpost, PDV Helios Fortress, and Tartarus Station are all considered stations under Law 2.
- Military craft: Ships with MIL, TSF, and PDV IFF designations are considered military craft under Law 4. Note that Law 4 also has ADS treat unidentified craft as military craft.

[color=yellow][bold]Law Clarifications:[/bold][/color]
- Law 2: You can chase targets you are in combat with to stations and engage them there, but if it has been too long and you've lost track of them, or you break off and disengage, you cannot begin combat if you catch them at a station later. This also applies to players fighting ADS; if they fight an ADS and the ADS hides in a safe zone, they can engage them, but if combat is broken off then they cannot.
- Law 4: The "If Feasible" part of Law 4 establishes that you should use methods to disarm military ships that do not pose a risk to the operators if reasonable. The primary method is giving ships a chance to willingly disarm by hailing them. There is intentional wiggle room as to what is and isn't considered feasible, but there are limitations, which can be seen in the examples sections below. Additionally, you can aim for crew on hostile vessels (IE, shooting back) in order to disable the ship faster, but once the vessel is disabled they are no longer valid targets, and would instead be considered under Law 3.

[bold]Try Peacefully Disarming under Law 4:[/bold]
- MIL or IFFless craft, no initial signs of hostility.
- TSF or PDV craft, no initial signs of hostility.

[bold]First Strike Allowed under Law 4:[/bold]
- Heavily armed capital class military or IFFless craft far more powerful than you.
- Military or IFFless craft approaching you at high speed with no prior communication.
- Military or IFFless craft which is part of a faction that you have learned has attacked ADS forces this shift.
- Military or IFFless craft that flee disarmament, refuse disarmament or fail to respond to hails in a reasonable time frame.
- Military or IFFless craft whose operator has given reason over comms to assume they are hostile to ADS, such as claiming to destroy or hunt ADS.

</Document>
